Guide to the Peter Newell Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Alfred Zantzinger Baker Jr. Papers, 1892-1986; Series VIII; 5.5; (13 boxes)
  - PETER NEWELL BIOGRAPHY PROJECT
    - Research Files - Family Members
      - McCormick, Howard
        - Correspondence re: papers donated to Cornell University, 1953-55 (Box 214, Folder 2895)
      - McCormick, Josephine Newell, 1948 (Box 214, Folder 2896)
      - Nankivel, Amanda Newell, 1926-34 (Box 214, Folder 2897)
        See also: Nankivel family letters filed with Claude Nankivel material, Box 214, folder 2898
      - Nankivel, Claude and Agnes
        - Correspondence with A. Z. Baker Jr., 1951-68 (Box 214, Folder 2898)
        - Family letters and ephemera, 1914-49 (Box 214, Folder 2899)
      - Nankivel, Gertrude John (Mrs. Guy), 1950, 1959 (Box 214, Folder 2900)
      - Nankivel, John Frederick, 1950, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 2901)
      - Newell family general information, 1941-81 (Box 214, Folder 2902)
      - Newell, Floyd and Laura, 1945-81 (Box 214, Folder 2903)
      - Newell, George Frederick, ca. 1922-75 (Box 214, Folder 2904)
      - Newell, Leona Dow Ashcraft notes from interview, 1946, n.d. (Box 214, Folder 2905)
      - Reynolds, Marion (May) Ashcraft, 1952-53 (Box 214, Folder 2906)
      - Worthen family, 1951-77 (Box 214, Folder 2907)
      - Worthen, Jesse and Luella Newell, 1941-77 (Box 214, Folder 2908)
    - Research Files - Locales and Associations
      Files in this section are arranged by state and town, then alphabetically by person or institution within. General information files precede subject files.
      - California
        - Clover, Samuel, 1977 (Box 215, Folder 2909)
      - Colorado
        - General information, 1940-82, n.d. (Box 215, Folder 2910)
      - Connecticut, Riverton
        - Baggs, Marion, 1943-52, n.d. (Box 215, Folder 2911)
        - Brown, John N., 1929-37 (Box 215, Folder 2912)
      - Connecticut, Westport
        - Boyd, Edward Finley, 1948, 1965 (Box 215, Folder 2913)
      - Illinois
        - General information, 1941-64 (Box 215, Folder 2914)
      - Illinois, Bushnell
        - General information, 1940-83 (Box 215, Folder 2915)
        - Newspaper notices, 1873-84, copied from microfilm, n.d. (Box 215, Folder 2916)
        - Boyd, Nellie Taylor, 1952 (Box 215, Folder 2917)
        - Cline, Cora Boyle, 1943, n.d. (Box 215, Folder 2918)
        - Dertlinger, J. E., 1941-48 (Box 215, Folder 2919)
        - Hersey, Peter, n.d. (Box 215, Folder 2920)
        - Jackson, Franklin, 1972, 1976 (Box 215, Folder 2921)
        - Kuhn, Charles, 1972 (Box 215, Folder 2922)
        - Madison, Marie, 1976-77 (Box 215, Folder 2923)
        - Miles, Alma DeVore, 1944 (Box 215, Folder 2924)
        - Newell diary transcriptions, ca. 1942 (Box 215, Folder 2925)
        - Parsons, Emma Dawson, 1943-46 (Box 215, Folder 2926)
        - Pemberton, Bess, 1963-70 (Box 215, Folder 2927)
        - Pinckly, Mack M., 1975 (Box 215, Folder 2928)
        - Railroads, 1940-63 (Box 215, Folder 2929)
        - Ritchie, Minnie Humes, 1944-45 (Box 215, Folder 2930)
        - Silberer, Howard, 1966-72 (Box 215, Folder 2931)
        - Silberer, Howard, 1973-81 (Box 215, Folder 2932)
        - Sperry, C. E., 1943-44 (Box 215, Folder 2933)
        - Wann, Curtis M., 1942-47 (Box 215, Folder 2934)
      - Illinois, Canton
        - General information, 1944-62 (Box 216, Folder 2935)
      - Illinois, Hills Grove
        - General information, 1945, 1951 (Box 216, Folder 2936)
      - Illinois, Jacksonville
        - General information, 1950-85 (Box 216, Folder 2937)
        - Black, Dr. G. V., 1955-58 (Box 216, Folder 2938)
        - Carver-Hixson family, 1946-77, n.d. (Box 216, Folder 2939)
        - Fairbank family, 1946-56 (Box 216, Folder 2940)
        - Goltra, Mabel H. correspondence, 1946-57 (Box 216, Folder 2941)
        - Goltra, Mabel H. clippings, etc., 1946-57 (Box 216, Folder 2942)
        - Heinl, Frank, 1925-45 (Box 216, Folder 2943)
        - Howard, Ralph W., 1955 (Box 216, Folder 2944)
        - Irving, Frank, 1942-46 (Box 216, Folder 2945)
        - Jacksonville Business College, 1942-55 (Box 216, Folder 2946)
        - Nichols, Samuel W., 1953-57 (Box 216, Folder 2947)
        - Storrs, Henry E., 1975-77 (Box 216, Folder 2948)
        - Stringham, Ralph, 1955 (Box 216, Folder 2949)
        - Tanner, Frederick C., 1963 (Box 216, Folder 2950)
        - Trabue, Ellie, 1945-47 (Box 216, Folder 2951)
        - Waddell, Mabel Brown, 1946 (Box 216, Folder 2952)
      - Illinois, Macomb
        - General information, 1943-75 (Box 216, Folder 2953)
        - Gumbart, L. F., 1943-45 (Box 216, Folder 2954)
      - Illinois, Rice's Corners
        - General information, 1944-45 (Box 216, Folder 2955)
      - Illinois, Springfield
        - General information, 1948-64 (Box 216, Folder 2956)
      - Nebraska, Bloomington
        - General information, 1970-72 (Box 216, Folder 2957)
      - New Jersey, Fort Lee
        - General information, 1954-85 (Box 217, Folder 2958)
      - New Jersey, Leonia: general information
        - "The Book of the Leonia Semi-Centennial", 1944 (Box 217, Folder 2959)
        - Clippings, 1937-83 (Box 217, Folder 2960)
        - Correspondence and notes, 1958-75, n.d. (Box 217, Folder 2961)
        - "County Portrait," from Bergen County Panorama [1941] photocopy, 1963 (Box 217, Folder 2962)
        - "Historic Leonia: Sketches by Leonia Artists" notecards, 1975 (Box 217, Folder 2963)
        - "Leonia," in History of Bergen County, New Jersey [1900] photocopy, n.d. (Box 217, Folder 2964)
        - "Leonia: an Ideal Residential Community" supplement to Life, 1933 Nov 10 (Box 217, Folder 2965)
        - "Leonia: The Place to Make Your Home" [1926] photocopy, 1958, 1971 (Box 217, Folder 2966)
        - "Salute to Leonia, New Jersey," transcript of WCBS radio show, 1954, 1956 (Box 217, Folder 2967)
        - Trolley lines, n.d. (Box 217, Folder 2968)
      - New Jersey, Leonia
        - Allison, John, 1922-81 (Box 217, Folder 2969)
        - American Legion, 1954-85 (Box 217, Folder 2970)
        - Beecher, Janet
          See: Norton family, Box 218, folder 3013
        - Blaisdell, Ward, 1977 (Box 217, Folder 2971)
        - Bogert, Lela L., 1948, 1953 (Box 217, Folder 2972)
        - Boyd, J. Rutherford and Harriet, 1930-83 (Box 217, Folder 2973)
        - Bradley, Frances Sage and Horace: correspondence, 1938-57 (Box 217, Folder 2974)
        - Bradley, Frances Sage and Horace: correspondence with children, 1945-59 (Box 217, Folder 2975)
        - Bradley, Frances Sage and Horace: correspondence with children, 1964-75, n.d. (Box 217, Folder 2976)
        - Bradley, Frances Sage and Horace: correspondence with Smith College and Emory University libraries, 1970 (Box 217, Folder 2977)
        - Bradley, Frances Sage and Horace: notes (Box 217, Folder 2978)
        - Carter, Freeland A., 1944-58 (Box 217, Folder 2979)
        - Chapman, Charles S. correspondence, 1930-83 (Box 217, Folder 2980)
        - Chapman, Charles S. clippings and publications, 1928-65, n.d. (Box 217, Folder 2981)
        - Chapman, Charles S. Memoirs of Charles S. Chapman, N.A. by Ada Chapman, 1964 (Box 217, Folder 2982)
        - Chapman, Charles S. "Portrait in Black and White: A Sketch of the Life of Charles Chapman N.A.," by Margaret Loomis, in The Ogdensburg Republican Journal (1932) photocopies from microfilm, 1963 (Box 217, Folder 2983)
        - Coe, Albert, 1950, 1959 (Box 218, Folder 2984)
        - Comstock, Enos: correspondence with family, 1932-76 (Box 218, Folder 2985)
        - Comstock, Enos: correspondence with family, 1977-79 (Box 218, Folder 2986)
        - Cornwell, Dean, ca. 1932-75 (Box 218, Folder 2987)
        - Covey, Arthur, 1927-75 (Box 218, Folder 2988)
        - Daugherty, James, 1945-75 (Box 218, Folder 2989)
        - Dawes, Dexter, 1949-75 (Box 218, Folder 2990)
        - Dunn, Harvey: correspondence and notes, 1938-71, n.d. (Box 218, Folder 2991)
        - Dunn, Harvey: "An Evening in the Classroom", 1934 (Box 218, Folder 2992)
        - Edmundson, Mrs., 1950, 1959 (Box 218, Folder 2993)
        - Farwell, Hermon W., 1949 (Box 218, Folder 2994)
        - Fay, Clark, 1948-78 (Box 218, Folder 2995)
        - Flockhart, Lolita
          See: Van Dearing Perrine, Box 218, folder 3016
        - Gausmann, Colonel R. W., 1950 (Box 218, Folder 2996)
        - Gaze, Olive
        - Gilmore, Helen, 1975 (Box 218, Folder 2997)
        - Gismond, Rebecca, 1948, 1953 (Box 218, Folder 2998)
        - Greene, Robert H., 1948, 1962 (Box 218, Folder 2999)
        - Hixson, Arthur Warren, 1953-63 (Box 218, Folder 3000)
        - Horne, Herman H., 1942-46, n.d. (Box 218, Folder 3001)
        - Hughes, J. Harold and Carter, 1948-76 (Box 218, Folder 3002)
        - Jones, Edmund Hazen and Sara, 1945-57 (Box 218, Folder 3003)
        - Kline, Hibberd, 1943-75 (Box 218, Folder 3004)
        - Leich, Chester, 1975 (Box 218, Folder 3005)
        - Leonia School of Illustration, 1974, n.d. (Box 218, Folder 3006)
        - Ludwig family
          See: Wyckoff family, Box 219, folder 3045
        - Mabie, George, 1974-84 (Box 218, Folder 3007)
        - MacLean, Katherine Allison, 1957-75 (Box 218, Folder 3008)
        - Mathieu, Hubert, 1949 (Box 218, Folder 3009)
        - Meysenburg family
        - Moore, W. D., 1948-74 (Box 218, Folder 3010)
        - Morriss, Fannie Huntington, 1957 (Box 218, Folder 3011)
        - Newell house, 165 Leonia Avenue, 1984-85 (Box 218, Folder 3012)
        - Norton/Meysenburg families, 1945-58 (Box 218, Folder 3013)
        - Noyes, William and Anna, 1947-76 (Box 218, Folder 3014)
        - Osler, Frederic, 1948-76, n.d. (Box 218, Folder 3015)
        - Palisade Art Association
          See: John Allison, Box 217, folder 2969
        - Peck, Clara Elsene
          See: John Scott Williams, Box 219, folder 3042
        - Perrine, Van Dearing, 1929-86 (Box 218, Folder 3016)
        - Players Guild of Leonia, 1977, n.d. (Box 218, Folder 3017)
        - Pond, Richard C., 1947, 1966 (Box 218, Folder 3018)
        - Presbyterian Church, 1936-58 (Box 218, Folder 3019)
        - Reed, Horatio and Hoyt Coe: correspondence, 1947 (Box 218, Folder 3020)
        - Reed, Hoyt Coe: correspondence, 1966-87 (Box 218, Folder 3021)
        - Reynard, Grant and Gwendolyn, 1949-75 (Box 218, Folder 3022)
        - Schilling, Alexander, 1937-64 (Box 219, Folder 3023)
        - Searles, Edna Young, 1948 (Box 219, Folder 3024)
        - Segard, Christian P., 1950 (Box 219, Folder 3025)
        - Shedd, Cornelia B., 1949, 1965 (Box 219, Folder 3026)
        - Smith, Howard Peck, 1948-50 (Box 219, Folder 3027)
        - Spear, Willard M., 1948-83 (Box 219, Folder 3028)
        - Stagg family, 1940, 1948 (Box 219, Folder 3029)
        - Stedman, Marshall, 1948, n.d. (Box 219, Folder 3030)
        - Stote, Amos, 1947, 1954 (Box 219, Folder 3031)
        - Street, Frank and May, 1953-75 (Box 219, Folder 3032)
        - Sumner, Mrs. Graham, 1947 (Box 219, Folder 3033)
        - Talmage family, 1949-72 (Box 219, Folder 3034)
        - Taylor family, 1949, 1975 (Box 219, Folder 3035)
        - Timmons, Edna, 1949 (Box 219, Folder 3036)
        - Townley, Clifford, 1963, 1983 (Box 219, Folder 3037)
        - Townsend, Harry, 1946-47 (Box 219, Folder 3038)
        - Townsend, Leland, 1949-74 (Box 219, Folder 3039)
        - Tyson, Frances Bartlett, 1948, 1952 (Box 219, Folder 3040)
        - Whitley, Abram, 1950, 1956 (Box 219, Folder 3041)
        - Williams, John Scott and Clara Peck, 1945-76 (Box 219, Folder 3042)
        - Williams, John W. and Charlotte, 1948-65 (Box 219, Folder 3043)
        - Williams, Verne, 1950-60 (Box 219, Folder 3044)
        - Wyckoff family correspondence, 1944-62 (Box 219, Folder 3045)
        - Wyckoff family correspondence, 1978-85 (Box 219, Folder 3046)
        - Wyndham, Olive
        - Yalden, J. Ernest G., 1937-58 (Box 219, Folder 3047)
        - Young, Art, 1939-48, n.d. (Box 219, Folder 3048)
        - Young, Mahonri: correspondence with Brigham Young University, 1965-85 (Box 219, Folder 3049)
        - Young, Mahonri: correspondence with M. Lewis Dittmore, 1973-75 (Box 219, Folder 3050)
        - Young, Mahonri: photographs of Newell maquette, n.d. (Box 219, Folder 3051)
        - Young, Mahonri: correspondence with Young family, 1937-72 (Box 219, Folder 3052)
        - Miscellaneous correspondence and questionnaires, 1948-75 (Box 219, Folder 3053)
        - Miscellaneous obituaries and biographies, 1935-80 (Box 219, Folder 3054)
      - New Jersey, Nutley
        - General information, 1983 (Box 219, Folder 3055)
      - New York, Little Neck
        - General information, 1955-86, n.d. (Box 220, Folder 3056)
        - Squires, Charles C., 1910-79, n.d. (Box 220, Folder 3057)
      - New York, New York
        - General information, 1976, n.d. (Box 220, Folder 3058)
        - Art Students League, 1939-78, n.d. (Box 220, Folder 3059)
          See also: Box 221, Folder 3096
        - Authors' League of America, 1958, 1960 (Box 220, Folder 3060)
        - Bell Syndicate, 1940-72 (Box 220, Folder 3061)
        - Bland, Harry
          See: Chinatown Dinner Group, Box 220, folder 3067
        - Bradley, Horace
          See: Box 217, Folders 2974-2978
        - Breck, George, 1957-75 (Box 220, Folder 3062)
        - Buehrmann, Elizabeth, 1949-62 (Box 220, Folder 3063)
        - Carruth, F. Hayden correspondence, 1953-84 (Box 220, Folder 3064)
        - Carruth, F. Hayden notes, poems and clipping from Carruth's papers, 1901-24 (Box 220, Folder 3065)
        - Carruth, F. Hayden photocopies of letters (1898-1921) in the New York Public Library, 1972 (Box 220, Folder 3066)
        - Chinatown Dinner Group, 1953-75, n.d. (Box 220, Folder 3067)
        - Columbia University, 1956 (Box 220, Folder 3068)
        - Congregational Church, Morrisania, 1976-77 (Box 220, Folder 3069)
        - Cory, Kate, 1944 (Box 220, Folder 3070)
        - Cox, Kenyon and Louise K., 1944-45 (Box 220, Folder 3071)
        - Curran, Grace (Mrs. Charles), 1944 (Box 220, Folder 3072)
        - Davies, Arthur B., 1975-76 (Box 220, Folder 3073)
        - Deming, Edwin W. correspondence, 1939-69 (Box 220, Folder 3074)
        - Deming, Edwin W. correspondence, 1970-83, n.d. (Box 220, Folder 3075)
        - Deming, Edwin W. biographical material and notes, 1925-56, n.d. (Box 220, Folder 3076)
        - Dove, Arthur, 1960, 1975 (Box 220, Folder 3077)
        - DuMond, Frank V., 1945-68 (Box 220, Folder 3078)
        - Frost, Arthur B., 1943-83 (Box 220, Folder 3079)
        - Gibson, Charles Dana, 1944-82 (Box 220, Folder 3080)
        - Held, John
        - Heller, Eugenie, 1952-54 (Box 220, Folder 3081)
        - Herford, Oliver, 1935-52 (Box 220, Folder 3082)
        - Jenks, Tudor, 1957-62 (Box 220, Folder 3083)
        - Lamb family, 1945 (Box 220, Folder 3084)
        - Lauber, Joseph, 1945-48 (Box 220, Folder 3085)
        - Major, Ernest L., 1945 (Box 221, Folder 3086)
        - Melville, Herman, 1970-83 (Box 221, Folder 3087)
        - Perard, Victor, 1946-62 (Box 221, Folder 3088)
        - Rushmore, Arthur W., 1950-75 (Box 221, Folder 3089)
        - Salmagundi Club, 1959-78 (Box 221, Folder 3090)
        - Weitenkampf, Frank, 1945-79 (Box 221, Folder 3091)
        - Wilder, Arthur B., 1944 (Box 221, Folder 3092)
        - Williams, Gluyas, 1976, 1982 (Box 221, Folder 3093)
      - New York, Ripley
        - General, 1944-64 (Box 221, Folder 3094)
    - Research Files - Miscellaneous
      - Alice illustrations, 1962-80, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3095)
      - Archives of American Art, 1963-78, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3096)
      - Artists and illustrators
        - Biographies, A - E, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3097)
        - Biographies, F - Z, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3098)
        - Biographies, photocopies from Reed, The Illustrator in America, 1984 (Box 221, Folder 3099)
        - Obituaries, 1933-83 (Box 221, Folder 3100)
      - Author's query, The New York Times Book Review, 1952 Nov 9 (Box 221, Folder 3101)
      - Chronologies, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3102)
      - Correspondents, miscellaneous, 1932-83 (Box 221, Folder 3103)
      - Fisher, William Murrell, 1964 (Box 221, Folder 3104)
      - Goodspeed's Bookshop, 1957-66 (Box 221, Folder 3105)
      - Lennon, Florence Becker, 1945 (Box 221, Folder 3106)
      - Library of Congress, 1943-76 (Box 221, Folder 3107)
      - Lists of names and addresses (Box 221, Folder 3108)
      - Maps and floor plans of Newell homes (Box 221, Folder 3109)
      - Montgomery Ward, 1960-61 (Box 221, Folder 3110)
      - New York Public Library, 1953-79 (Box 221, Folder 3111)
      - New York State Library, Albany, 1958-64 (Box 221, Folder 3112)
      - Newell bibliographies, n.d. (Box 221, Folder 3113)
      - Newell book reprints, 1966-75, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3114)
      - Newell contemporaries responses to inquiries, including:, 1944-65 (Box 222, Folder 3115)
        Cady, Harrison
        Christy, Howard Chandler
        Edwards, George Wharton
        Flagg, James Montgomery
        Goldberg, Rube
        Mumford, Lewis
        Parrish, Maxfield
        Shinn, Everett
        Sterner, Albert
        Tarkington, Booth
      - Newell, George Glenn and Newell, Peter (1916- ), 1970-75 (Box 222, Folder 3116)
      - Newell in catalogues and indexes (Box 222, Folder 3117)
      - Newell in other collections
        - Positive responses, 1955-86 (Box 222, Folder 3118)
          See also: Walt Reed, Box 222, folder 3133
        - Negative responses, 1956-87 (Box 222, Folder 3119)
        - Notes, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3120)
      - Newell in serials, 1964, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3121)
      - Newellesque novelties, 1939, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3122)
      - Notes by Helen N. Gordon, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3123)
      - Notes from interviews, 1949, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3124)
      - Notes on magazines and humor (Box 222, Folder 3125)
      - Notes, random, 1948-74, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3126)
      - Notes, random, 1980, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3127)
      - Notes, random (Box 222, Folder 3128-3130)
        See also: Card Files in Box 223, folder 3138
      - Obituaries, 1950-81 (Box 222, Folder 3131)
      - Partridge, Henry M., 1934-35 (Box 222, Folder 3132)
      - Reed, Walt, 1977-79 (Box 222, Folder 3133)
      - Symmetry and duck-rabbit pictures, 1960-65 (Box 222, Folder 3134)
      - U.S. Department of Commerce, Patent Office, 1930-60 (Box 222, Folder 3135)
      - Verbeek, Gustave, n.d. (Box 222, Folder 3136)
      - Walt Disney Productions, 1956 (Box 222, Folder 3137)
      - Card Files - index of people and publications, miscellaneous notes, 1940-85 (Box 223)
  - PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE AND PAPERS
    - Baker, Alfred Z., Sr., 1921, 1928 (Box 224, Folder 3138)
    - Baker, Alfred Z., Sr., estate of
      - Baker, J. Paul, 1941-42 (Box 224, Folder 3139)
      - Baltimore Trust Company, 1942 (Box 224, Folder 3140)
      - Copyrights, 1942, 1945 (Box 224, Folder 3141)
      - Cremation receipt, 1940 (Box 224, Folder 3142)
      - Isabey (Jean Baptiste) miniature, n.d. (Box 224, Folder 3143)
      - Legal correspondence, 1940-41 (Box 224, Folder 3144)
      - Legal correspondence, 1942 (Box 224, Folder 3145)
      - Lowry, Glenn, 1941 Jul (Box 224, Folder 3146)
      - Morton, Walter A. re: estate auction, 1941-42 (Box 224, Folder 3147)
      - Notes, miscellaneous, [1941-42] (Box 224, Folder 3148)
      - Postal receipts, 1941-42 (Box 224, Folder 3149)
      - Reed, Hoyt Coe and Thomas, 1941 (Box 224, Folder 3150)
    - Brown Thomson Inc., 1936 (Box 224, Folder 3151)
    - Champe, Carlton, 1976-78 (Box 224, Folder 3152)
    - Cosgrove, Betty (Helen) Baker, 1920-77, n.d. (Box 224, Folder 3153)
    - Diplomas, 1922, 1927
      See: Oversize, Box 240, Folders 3311-3312
    - Gordon, Helen Newell Baker, 1923 Dec 26 (Box 224, Folder 3154)
    - Gordon, Lee, n.d. (Box 224, Folder 3155)
    - Harper & Brothers/Harper & Row, Inc.
      - Royalty statements, 1955-65 (Box 224, Folder 3156)
      - Royalty statements, 1966-75 (Box 224, Folder 3157)
    - Lydecker, Sally McCormick, 1955 (Box 224, Folder 3158)
    - Miscellaneous correspondents, 1908-75, n.d. (Box 224, Folder 3159)
    - Newell and Gordon memorials in Brookville Cemetery, Pennsylvania, 1972 (Box 224, Folder 3160)
    - Personal notes, n.d. (Box 224, Folder 3161)
    - Ufer, Walter and Mary, 1928-31 (Box 224, Folder 3162)
    - Yalden, J. Ernest G. Universal scale, 1892 (Box 224, Folder 3163)
- Work by Other Artists, 1880-1930; Series IX; 16.45; (10 boxes) + 9 oil paintings
  The series consists of artwork by Peter Newell's peers and family members. Portraits of Newell appear first, followed by other works that have been grouped by media and arranged alphabetically by artist within the classifications: Drawings and Illustrations; Oil Paintings; Prints; and Sculpture.
  - PORTRAITS OF PETER NEWELL
    Drawings filed by artist; media include ink, pencil and crayon on paper.
    - Baker, Alfred Z., ca. 1900 (Box 225, Folder 3164)
    - Baker, Alfred Z., 1901 (Box 225, Folder 3165)
    - Baker, Alfred Z., n.d. (Box 225, Folder 3166)
    - Deming, Edward W., 1883 (Box 225, Folder 3167)
    - Nadherny (?), 1906 (Box 225, Folder 3168)
  - DRAWINGS AND ILLUSTRATIONS
    Drawings by Newell's peers are organized into two groups according to size, and arranged alphabetically by the artist's name (or initials, if unknown) within. Many of the drawings are stamped with a copyright for Harpers and have editor's markings and job numbers. Some have been identified as having been published and their dates are given, while others have only the stamped copyright date. Media include ink, pencil and watercolor on paper and paperboard.
    - Abbey, Edwin Austin, "She by the river sat...", n.d. (Box 226, Folder 3169)
    - Cooke, Claudine Nankivel [Self-portrait holiday card], n.d. (Box 226, Folder 3170)
    - Davidson, Jo [Five men in capsizing boat], n.d. (Box 226, Folder 3171)
    - DeRiyke, A. M. [Landscape], 1901 (Box 226, Folder 3172)
    - Durand, F. L.(?) [Portrait of a woman] (Box 226, Folder 3173)
    - F., W. (?) "Late Summer Afternoon", n.d. (Box 226, Folder 3174)
    - Kemble, Edward Windsor, "I'm mad clean through", 1912 June 28 (Box 226, Folder 3175)
    - Linnell, Harry A. [Woman, Newport] inscribed: "sketched Aug 2.94. for Peter Newell at Newport, RI.", 1894 (Box 226, Folder 3176)
    - P. "Pebbles No 6", n.d. (Box 226, Folder 3177)
    - P., W. [Figures in staircase], n.d. (Box 226, Folder 3178)
    - Pourriol, Charles, [Ladies and child at seaside] inscribed: "a Madame Newell en bon souvenir", 1904 (Box 226, Folder 3179)
    - Ralph, Lester, "Laden with plunder" from "In the Wake of the War" by Julian Ralph, for Harper's Monthly, 1898 Mar (Box 226, Folder 3180)
    - Steele, Frederick Dorr, "With Apologies to Peter Newell", 1895 (Box 226, Folder 3181)
    - Townsend, Harry
      - [Portrait of a man], n.d. (Box 226, Folder 3182)
      - [Waterside scene in China], n.d. (Box 226, Folder 3183)
    - Williams, John Scott, "Comrades" for Collier's (Box 226, Folder 3184)
    - Woolf, Michael Angelo, [Two female urchins below house on hill, used in "Truth"], 1897 Jul 17 (Box 226, Folder 3185)
    - Young, Arthur, [Bearded man in rocker], inscribed: "For my fellow artist Clen Newell Arthur Young N.Y. May 26 1901" (Box 226, Folder 3186)
    - Unidentified artist
      - "Giddep! Nap. Our best costomer's gone an left us.", n.d. (Box 226, Folder 3187)
      - [Soldiers/hunters on horseback], n.d. (Box 226, Folder 3188)
      - "The Wood Mouse, after Giacomelli", 1880 Mar 12
    - Ashe, Edmund M., "They are all hollow" from "A Will and a Way" by Margaret Sutton Briscoe, for Harper's Monthly, 1898 May (Box 227, Folder 3189)